Hello

I'm Sony Arianto Kurniawan

FULL-STACK ENGINEER



Apartment Casablanca East Residence Tower Dallas, 9th Floor, 18th Unit Jalan Pahlawan Revolusi No. 2, Jakarta Timur, 13430, Indonesia +62 819 0525 8602 sony@sony-ak.com or sonyakknowledgecenter@gmail.com

GitHub: https://github.com/sonyarianto

Web: https://sony-ak.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sonyarianto/

Skills

I am a full-stack engineer with more than 10 years experience in the IT industry. My skills include software development with PHP, Symfony, JavaScript and database technology. On the back-end, I also have experience with Linux administration and cloud platform such as AWS, GCP and other similar cloud services.

Experience

FEB 2015 - DEC 2020

PT. LIFULL Media Indonesia, Jakarta - Software Engineer & Infrastructure Lead

- Development of web application for company and external clients. On Symfony, Laravel, PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, APIs and other related technology stack.
- Managing cloud infrastructure for the company on Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (GCP) and other Linux based stack.
- Managing small team of engineer
- LIFULL is multinational company headquartered in Tokyo, Japan.

JUL 2009 - DEC 2014

PT. Earthstone Resources, Jakarta - Software Engineer & Infrastructure Lead

- Development and integration on company website projects in Bangalore and Jakarta, using PHP, MySQL, APIs and other related stack.
- Managing small team of engineer
- Earthstone is multinational company on mining industry

MAY 2007 - JUN 2009

PT. Solusi Media Selular, Jakarta - Software Engineer

 Development on company projects using PHP, CakePHP, MySQL, SMS gateway and other related stack.

APR 2006 - APR 2007

PT. Pentacahaya Computindo, Jakarta - Software Engineer

Development on company web projects using PHP, MySQL and other related stack.

JAN 2005 - OCT 2005

PT. Media Teknologi Informasi, Jakarta - Technical Editor

Managing small technical editorial team for IT enterprise magazine

NOV 2002 - DEC 2004

Ciputra Cyber Institute, Surabaya – *Software Engineer and Database Administrator* (DBA)

- Development on desktop application for company and web on Active Server Pages (ASP) technology.
- Managing database infrastructure on SQL Server

JUL 2000 - OCT 2002

PT. MYOHDOTCOM Indonesia Tbk., Malang - Software Engineer

Development on desktop application for company on Delphi and SQL Server technology.

Education

1995 - 2001

Sekolah Tinggi Informatika & Komputer Indonesia, Malang - Bachelor Degree (S1)

Why me?

I can work with attention to detail and quality. I can learn new things quickly and adapt to new environment. I can create good solution based on requirements on constraints effectively and efficiently.

Skills (in detail)

My journey as an engineer makes me have opportunity to get in touch with several tools, programming language or libraries that maybe fits with your organization. Here is the detail.

Programming Language/Framework:

• PHP, Symfony, Laravel, JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Database:

• MySQL, ArangoDB (nosql)

Cloud Platform:

• AWS, GCP (mostly on Linux platform)

Development tools and others:

• Ansible, Docker, Puppeteer, APIs, Git, data scraping

Other stack/technology maybe still not used frequently during my career journey, such as Go or React, but I can learn to fit your needs.